This trick is just something I thought you might find cool.
How do you transition the player from anywhere in the room to where you want them?
Cinematography is ever more relevant in games.
Walk through a door, cutscene.
Fight someone?
Cutscene.
We don't want our transitions to cutscenes to be jarring.
The God of War developers wanted the entire game to be in one single shot.
Which is absolutely crazy to even conceive.
But there are still some people who believe in witchcraft it would seem.
In this scene, Kratos can finish this fight anywhere in this space,
but then needs to be over here.
How would you do this and still keep it in one shot?
This is a whip pan transition.
You would have seen them in the travel vlogs where you all vicariously live through.
Sad wallet.
They get used in big productions too.
Rotate out to create motion blur?
Rotate in creating motion blur?
Hide the cut somewhere in the middle.
Taking inspiration from this, here's how God of War does it.
The camera gets way in close to make us focus on the characters.
Spin the characters to blur everything in the background.
Hide the unnatural teleport or slide in the motion blur.
It's actually really effective.
You probably didn't notice it until I told you.
It's important that the player is focusing on the foreground and not the background though.
Otherwise they will notice what we are doing.
This is why the foregrounds of these scenes have such pronounced movements.
There's a bunch more one minute tips like this one in this playlist.
Maybe take five minutes to check a few out.
Subscribe!